我不做猎人了
I don't hunt anymore.
-你退出了  -是的
- You quit? - Yeah.
是什么让你就那么退出了
What could possibly make you stop just like that?
是因为女孩吗
Was there a girl?
没错  是有过
Yeah. There was.
后来又没了
And then there wasn't.
你得知道  我不是突然就退出了
You need to know, I didn't just drop out.
我找到了一些东西
I found something.
-是  她叫什么  -艾米利亚
- Yeah, what was her name? - Amelia.
莫瑞森教授  你的政府需要你  先生
Professor Morrison, your government needs you, sir.
天啊  你在哪儿找到的这家伙
My god, where'd you find this guy?
他可是这领域最权威的专业人士
Supposed to be a top expert in his field.
-还有一块碑  -对
- Wait, there's another tablet? - Yes.
就是说还有神之语
So another word of God.
到底有多少神之语啊
How many words of God are there?
我一年前才成为先知的
I just became a prophet, like, a year ago.
-这块碑有名字吗  -"恶魔"
- Well, did this tablet have a name? - "Demons."
恶魔怎么了
What about demons?
从我读到的来看
As far as I could tell...
差不多是关于恶魔的一切
Everything.
凯文
Kevin!
开什么玩笑
You've got to be kidding me!
上面说什么
What's it say?
既然我们没了石碑
Since we lost the tablet,
凯文觉得我们不需要他了
Kevin figures we don't need him.
没错  但是克劳力有石碑
Yeah, but Crowley still does.
那孩子想什么呢
What's that kid thinking?!
保护他是我们的责任
He was our responsibility.
-那我们去找他  -好
- Let's find him. - Okay.
如今
明尼苏达州  明尼阿波里斯市
祝贺你  跑得真快啊
Congratulations. You're fast.
我常做有氧运动[我吃了不少心]
I do a lot of cardio.
《凶鬼恶灵》 第八季 第三集
心 痛
在炼狱待了一年  什么妖怪都跑出来了
Wow. Guy goes to purgatory for a year, all hell breaks loose.
你听听这个
Check this out.
明尼阿波里斯一个慢跑者的心被人掏走
A jogger in Minneapolis gets his heart ripped out.
不是在打比方吧
I'm guessing literally?
要不我也不会感兴趣
Only way that interests me.
没完呢  六个月前还有一篇报道
And then, there's another article from six months ago.
同样的事情  也是在明尼阿波里斯
Same thing happens, also in Minneapolis.
这说明什么呢
What does that tell us?
千万别去明尼阿波里斯
Stay out of Minneapolis.
同一个城市中两个人被掏心  间隔六个月
Two hearts ganked, same city, six months apart.
这肯定是种什么仪式  老弟
I mean, that's got to be a ritual, man.
至少也该是个
Or at least some sort of
被附身的  爱吃心脏的疯子蝙蝠怪
a heart-sucking, possessed, satanic, crack-whore bat.
什么东西
A what?
这是我们的活儿
It's a case.
咱们动身去瞧瞧吧
Look, I say we hang out the shingle again and ride.
我们手头有事做  迪恩
We're on a case, Dean.
咱们得先找到凯文和石碑
Kevin and the demon tablet need to be found,
掏心怪物再说吧
so heart guy takes a number.
我们为了找凯文
Uh, we just spent a week chasing our asses
已经瞎转悠一周了
trying to lock Kevin down, okay?
看看我们  我们.,.
And look at us. We're --
我们这是在哪儿
Where the hell are we?
农贸市场
Farmers' market.
有机食品
Organic.
怎么了  我休假一年
What? I had a year off.
尽情享受美好生活来着
I took the time to enjoy the good things.
将我们的职责抛在脑后
While avoiding doing what we actually do.
迪恩  你每次说这话真就那么爽吗
Wow, Dean, does it make you feel that much better every time you say it?
行了  老弟  我懂
All right, man, look, I get it.
你这一年做做瑜伽  弹弹琴
You took a year off to do yoga and play the lute,
随便你  但现在我回来了
whatever, but I'm back.
行吗  我们回来了
Okay, we're back,
所以我们得行走江湖  斩妖除魔
which means that we walk and kill monsters at the same time.
我们会找到凯文的
We'll find Kevin.
但在此期间我们能不管这种事吗
But in the meantime, do we ignore stuff like this?
还是说让无辜的人死去吧
Or are innocent people supposed to die
你就买你的农产品
so that you can shop for produce?
这案子怪就怪在
Here's what's odd about this thing --
死者身上并没有砍伤或刀伤  没有切口
The guy wasn't chopped or cut into, no incision.
但他的心脏像颗桃核一样被揪了出来
But his heart was ripped out of him like a peach pit.
遭抢劫了吗
Was he robbed?
手机  手表和钱都还留在身上
Phone, watch, money all still on him.
有任何敌人吗
What about enemies?
他是来镇里开会的  在当地没有熟人
He was in town for a conference. No local connections.
你们在六个月前发现一起相同案件
You guys had another one of these about six months ago.
是  调查毫无结果
Yeah, and we hit a brick wall.
实在是查不下去
We had nothing to go on, really.
本来还以为有发现
Thought maybe we got lucky here.
公园摄像头拍到了一些东西
A park surveillance camera picked up something.
那胖子是最后一个见到活着的死者的人
That chubby guy the last person to see the vic alive?
再就是凶手了
Other than the killer.
他叫保罗・海耶斯
Name's Paul Hayes.
我们叫他来问过话
We pulled him in for questioning.
你们为什么排除了他的嫌疑
So what makes you think he's clean?
到目前为止没法证实与他有关
Well, so far, no reason not to.
我是说  他承认曾见过死者一面
I mean, he said he briefly saw the victim,
超过了他  仅此而已
he ran out ahead, that was it.
你是说他没有跪下来
What, you mean he didn't fall to his knees
坦白自己把那家伙掏心了
and confess to gutting the guy?
不是  我们对他做了详细的背景调查
No. I mean we did a thorough check on the guy,
连张违章停车的罚单都没有
not so much as a parking ticket came up.
你们自己看看他
I mean, look at him.
我是说  他是挺能跑  可他又不是雷神
I mean, sure, he can run a little bit, but Thor he ain't.
你说他能抓住健壮的弗雷迪
You think he's gonna grab Freddy Fitness here
把他放倒  然后把心挖出来吗
and throw him down and rip out his heart?
我可不觉得
I don't think so.
抱歉我没有把他拉出去枪毙
Forgive me if I didn't take him out back and shoot him.
好吧  那...
Okay, uh so...
我们该去哪儿找这家伙
...any idea where we can find this guy?
抱歉
Sorry.
我正努力坚持我的营养和锻炼计划
I kind of try to stick to a nutrition and workout schedule.
要试试吗
Do you want a hit?
不用了  谢谢
I'm good. Thanks.
保罗  你超过了一名慢跑者  他随后被杀
So, Paul, you passed a runner who was later killed.
你跟他说过话吗
Did you speak with him at all?
我跟警察说过这事儿了
Yeah, I went over this with the cops.
我不认识他
I-I didn't know him.
也没跟他说过话
I had never spoken to him.
我超过了他  之后再没见过他  就这样
I ran past him. I never saw him again. The end.
真恶心
Oh. It's disgusting.
屎一样难喝  可是能让你年轻
It tastes like crap, but it keeps you young.
谢了  纤维太多
Thanks, uh -- uh... too much fiber.
没有的事
No such thing.
多谢
Thank you.
看见了吧
See?
保罗  我们注意到
Now, Paul, we couldn't help but notice
被你超越的慢跑者比你年轻很多
that the jogger you outraced was a good deal younger than you.
没错  而且更...
Yeah, and less, uh...
更苗条  你该看看从前的我
Uh, full-figured? You should've seen me before.
终日伏案  整晚看电视
Yeah, hugging a desk all day and watching TV all night,
吃各种油炸食品  真是要命
eating fried everything was killing me.
一年前我的健康出了大问题
I had a health scare about a year ago.
很遗憾
I'm sorry to hear that.
不必  它改变了我的生活
No, it changed my life.
我开始照顾自己
I mean, I started taking care of myself.
现在你的身体成了神殿
Now your body's a temple, huh?
我每天供奉礼拜
Where I worship every day.
怎么样
All right, so...what's the word?
你在保罗家有什么发现
What did you find poking around at Paul's?
都是平常东西  避孕套  发胶
Ah, just the usual -- condoms, hair gel.
没巫毒袋  没撒旦崇拜标志  没什么鬼东西
No hex bags, nothing satanic, nothing spooky.
所以说  他不像是个开膛手喽
So, he didn't seem like a guy who would be voted most likely to disembowel?
开膛手不是看出来的
No, they never do.
等等  还有一起
Wait a minute. Here's another one.
什么  谋杀吗
What, murder?
自助式心脏搭桥术
And a do-it-yourself heart bypass.
这件案子的两天后
Two days after this one.
明尼阿波利斯什么地方
What part of Minneapolis?
爱荷华州  艾姆斯
The Iowa part. Ames.
保罗当时正在这边接受质询
Well, Paul was here being questioned.
不可能是他
There's no way that could have been him.
艾姆斯警官因凶杀罪被捕
这家伙之前是警察
This guy was a cop.
跟六个月前发生的事一样
This is exactly what happened six months ago.
明尼阿波利斯  然后是艾姆斯
Minneapolis, then Ames.
看来你当时没留意
Guess you missed that one.
只是说说
I'm just saying.
亚瑟・斯温森  高级警官
Arthur Swenson. Real top-shelf officer.
从警二十年
20 years on the force.
他订了一张披萨  被害人去送货
He'd ordered a pizza, which the vic delivered.
爱荷华州  艾姆斯
然后呢
And then?
被害人的下一份订单没有送到
The vic didn't make his next drop-off.
在斯温森家门前的走道上发现了他的尸体
His body was found on the walk in front of swenson's.
他的心也没了
And he wasn't wearing a heart?
对  没有心脏
No. Heartless.
斯温森呢
And, uh, what about Swenson?
蜷缩在前门台阶上
Crumpled on the front stoop.
浑身都是血  泣不成声
Covered in blood, crying like a baby.
讽刺的是  他之前一周都在法庭上作证
Ironically, he had been in court all week, testifying.
抱歉
Excuse me.
请讲
Go ahead.
那明尼阿波利斯的凶案就不是他做的
So that couldn't have been him in Minneapolis.
我讨厌这种事
I hate when this happens.
这个叫亚瑟的家伙
So, this Arthur guy, what does --
他对此怎么说
What does he have to say?
没什么有用的
It's not real helpful.
他说了吗
So, you getting his statement?
算是吧
Uh, yeah, k-kind of.
或许不是
Probably not.
真后悔当初没好好听精神病讲座
It's too bad I dropped out of lunatic 101.
不管是什么  他好像是在重复
Whatever it is, it sounds like he's repeating it.
看他的眼睛
Look at his eyes.
亚瑟
Hey, Arthur...
是你一个人做的吗
Did you do this alone?
亚瑟  是不是有看不到的声音叫你去杀人
Arthur, did some invisible voice tell you you had to kill?
[非英语]
K'uhul ajaw, cacao, shi-jiiy!
你把他惹毛了
Oh, now you've pissed him off.
喂  亚特  我能叫你亚特吗
Hey, Art. Can I call you Art?
听着  我要在你手臂上倒圣水
Listen, I'm gonna sprinkle your arm with holy water,
如果你被恶魔附体  手臂会烧得冒烟
and it's gonna steam and burn if you're possessed by a demon.
他就是一蘑菇
He's a mushroom.
成了  没被附身
Okay, not possessed.
亚瑟  要不要告诉我你为什么这么做
Arthur, you want to tell us why you did this?
[非英语]
K'uhul ajaw, cacao, shi-jiiy.
好吧
Okay.
斯托雷郡警局
你怎么看
So, what do you think?
我更欣赏基思・理查兹的版本[滚石乐队成员]
Personally, I prefer the Keith Richards version.
你能听懂他说的词吗
Can you actually understand any of the words?
还未必是词呢
If they are words.
我听就是胡言乱语
Sounds like babble to me.
等一等
Wait a second.
什么
What?
我买了个翻译应用
I bought a translation app.
你买了个应用
You bought an app.
对
Yeah.
来  播放
Here, play it.
胡言乱语赢了  "未知语言"
And babble wins. "Language unknown."
桑伯拉探员
Agent Sambora.
什么
What?
卡诗医生  他是什么情况
So, Dr. Kashi, what are we looking at here,
精神崩溃吗
Some kind of psychotic break?
的确  下手非常狠
Oh, definitely. He was very thorough.
切断了视神经
Severed the optic nerve.
他决意要剜出这只眼睛
He was determined to remove the eye.
他用什么剜的
And he used, uh, what to cut with?
他看起来不怎么强壮
He doesn't look strong enough,
可是他掰下一块床沿当作刀用
but he broke off part of the bed frame and used it as a knife.
谢谢
Thank you.
那床可真该贴上警告标志
Wow. They should put warning labels on those beds.
我说了  是蓄意自残
Like I said -- determined.
我注意到他两只眼睛颜色不同
I noticed that he had two different-colored eyes.
是的  他遭遇过一次事故
Yes. Apparently, he was in an accident
一只眼球严重受损
where much of one eye was shattered.
靠眼球移植才修复了视力
His vision was saved with a transplant.
什么时候的事
When was this?
一年之前  差不多这个时候
A year ago, almost to the date.
而且有趣的是
And, interestingly,
他剜出来的正是移植的那颗眼球
it's the transplanted eye he chose to cut out.
真的吗
Really?
医生  请问一件事
Hey, let me ask you something, doc.
有没有可能查到器官捐献者是谁
Is it possible to trace the donor of a transplanted organ?
很难
Difficult.
也就是说有可能
But possible?
亚瑟・斯温森一年前做了眼球移植  对吗
Arthur Swenson had an eye transplant a year ago, right?
对
Yeah.
我记得保罗・海耶斯提到过
Well, I remembered that Paul Hayes was talking about
一年前他得了一场大病
a health scare he had a year ago
从而改变了他的生活
that changed his life,
所以我就调出了他在明尼阿波利斯的病例
so I pulled up his medical records from Minneapolis.
你说好好干  我就照做了
You want me on board, I'm on board.
你猜除了亚瑟・斯温森
Anyways, you want to guess who else,
还有谁在去年接受了移植手术
other than Arthur Swenson, had a transplant in the last year?
保罗・海耶斯
Paul Hayes?
被你发现了
I gave it away, didn't I?
那我们现在有两个疑犯
Okay, so we've got two suspects
在两个城市犯下了相同的罪
in two identical murders in two different cities
并且他们都在去年接受了器官移植
that both had organ transplants a year ago.
是的  还有
Yeah. Also...
你这话我喜欢
I love when there's an "Also."
我想了一下亚瑟・斯温森念叨的话
I got to thinking about all that stuff arthur Swenson was talking about.
或许你的翻译应用说它是未知语言
Maybe your translation app called it "Language unknown"
是因为这语言已经消失
because it's a dead language,
像是古希腊语或马恩岛语
like ancient Greek or Manx.
马恩岛
Manx?
所以我把他说话的音频发电邮
So I e-mailed an audio file of Arthur's mumbling
给了莫里森博士
to Dr. Morrison.
谁
Who?
莫里森博士  那个人类学教授
Dr. Morrison, the anthropology professor
亚马逊娘子军那次帮过我们
who helped us out with the Amazons.
我想起来了
Yes, okay. Okay.
好吧  我们上路吧
Well, let's get our asses on the road.
去哪儿
Headed to...?
如果这些案子是始于六个月前的连环事件
Well, if we are in a repeat of a cycle from six months ago,
在明尼阿波利斯和埃姆斯的凶案之后
then, after the murders in Minneapolis and in Ames,
第三起"袭心"事件发生在科罗拉多的博尔德
the next heart attack was in Boulder, Colorado.
后方入口
科罗拉多州  博尔德市
兰达
Randa?
你是奇克
Chick, right?
你今晚的表演可真棒
Loved your performance tonight.
台下要花不少功夫吧
Must take, uh, must take years of training.
事实上
Actually, uh...
我算是有天赋
I'm kind of a natural.
我通常不干这种事
You know, I don't normally do this kind of thing.
只是
Um, there's just --
你很特别
just something about you.
没错  事情越来越明朗了
All right, case is coming together.
一切都走上正轨了  伙计
Things are coming together, man.
我们一起办事  真棒
You and me. It is all good.
-跟你说话呢  -干什么
- Hey. - What?
你在想什么  有机番茄吗
What are you thinking about, organic tomatoes?
我什么都没想
I'm not thinking about anything.
我不知道你怎么样
I don't know about you,
但去年这一年我算是大彻大悟了
but this last year has given me a new perspective.
我懂  相信我
I hear you. Believe me.
我知道我的最佳状态
I know where I'm at my best,
就是像现在这样
and that is right here,
跟你一起驾车踏上危险的旅程
driving down crazy street next to you.
说的对
Makes sense.
当然
Yes, it does.
或许你根本不需要我
Or... maybe you don't need me.
或许你的最佳状态
I mean, maybe you're at your best
就是一个人披荆斩棘消灭所有怪物的时候
hacking and slicing your way through all the world's crap alone,
还不用跟别人多费口舌
not having to explain yourself to anybody.
这也没错
Yeah, that makes sense,
因为我还有好多其他的弟弟
seeing as I have so many other brothers
能跟我谈心呢
I can talk to about this stuff.
我不是想抛下你
Look, I'm not saying I'm bailing on you.
我是说  至少给彼此留点
I'm just saying make room for the possibility
有不同追求的余地
that we want different things.
我需要时间做些重要的事
I mean, I want my time to count for something.
我们做的不重要吗
So, what we do doesn't count?
你好
Yeah?
你好  卡诗医生
Hey, Dr. Kashi.
好的  谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
你可以再帮我查一个名字吗
Uh, could you run one more name for me?
保罗・海耶斯
Yeah -- Hayes, Paul.
捐献者是谁
Uh-huh. And the donor?
真的吗
Seriously?
还有多少人
How many others?
有没有科罗拉多州博尔德的人
Did anybody from Boulder, Colorado,
接受了某个器官
receive any of those organs?
好的  谢谢
Okay, thank you.
我保证这事会让你觉得很刺激
Well, this is gonna singe your axons.
她告诉我保罗・海耶斯的肾
She says that both Paul Hayes' kidney
和亚瑟・斯温森的眼睛都来自同一个人
and Arthur Swenson's new eye came from --
你准备好了吗
You ready for this? --
布里克・霍姆斯
Brick Holmes.
你说的不会是那个布里克・霍姆斯吧
You don't mean the Brick Holmes.
就是他
I do.
-那个全明星四分卫吗  -没错
- The all-pro quarterback? - Indeed.
那家伙在橄榄球界
Yeah, the guy played at the top of his game
称霸快上千年了吧
for like a million years, didn't he?
-没错  但去年他出车祸了  -是的
- Yeah, he -- he bought it in a car crash last year. - Yeah.
冲下了一座桥什么的
Nose-dived off a bridge or something.
他肯定签署了捐赠协议
He must've signed a donor card.
医生告诉你他捐了多少器官吗
Did the doctor say how many organs he donated?
包括那两个嫌犯  共八个
Including our two suspects? Eight.
-这么多  -对
- Eight? - Eight.
其中一个就在博尔德  对吗
Okay, um, and one of them's in Boulder, am I right?
坏消息是你说错了
You would be wrong. That's the bad news.
好消息是布里克就住在博尔德郊区
Good news is, Brick lived just outside of Boulder.
但是他死了
Well, Brick's dead.
没错  可是他是唯一的线索
Yeah, but he's all we got,
所以我们得去博尔德
so we are going to Boulder.
[咒语]
K'uhul ajaw, cacao, shi-jiiy.
我想说
I just want to say
对您儿子的事我们深表遗憾  霍姆斯女士
how sorry we are for your loss, Mrs. Holmes.
谢谢
Thank you.
布里克・霍姆斯可是我高中的偶像
You know, Brick Holmes was my idol back in high school.
太了不起了
Amazing career.
18年的职业生涯
18 pro seasons,
7次分区冠军  4次夺得超级碗
7 division championships, 4 super bowls --
每时每刻都处在巅峰
never slowed down a day.
布里克就是为比赛和运动而生的
Brick lived for competition and athletic perfection.
我想他的粉丝不会想到  他也只是凡人
I don't think it occurred to his fans that he was human,
跟我们一样
like the rest of us.
您知道他是个器官捐赠者吗
Do you know your son was an organ donor?
这跟联调局有什么关系吗
Does that make this a matter for the FBI?
我们刚说过了
Like we explained earlier,
我们其实是为调查另一件事而来
we're mostly here to dot some I's on a different matter.
几年前曾经有一次公众倡议活动
There was a public-awareness thing a few years ago.
不少明星运动员都签了字
A lot of star athletes signed on.
布里克当时肯定没多想
I'm sure Brick didn't think twice about it,
因为他从没想过自己会死
since he never thought he was going to die.
不少运动员都是这种心态吧
A lot of jocks are like that, I guess.
我禁不住要想
You know, I-I can't help wonder
那晚桥上到底发生了什么
what happened that night on that bridge.
车流不多
There was light traffic,
不是醉驾  也没有刹车痕
no alcohol involved, no skid marks.
一流的运动员  身手敏捷
Big-time athlete, reflexes like a cat,
他怎么就冲下了大桥
how is it that he just drives off the side of a bridge?
那些意想不到的事情发生的时候
When things happen that aren't supposed to happen,
才被称为意外吧
they're called accidents, I believe.
不用说  大家都熟知布里克的职业生涯
So, everybody knows about Brick's football career, obviously,
他的私生活却无人知晓
but no one knows much about his personal life.
他结过婚吗
Was he ever married?
他心里只有橄榄球  为此他付出了全部
Just to the game. He gave it everything he had.
这样的生活可不容易
It's a difficult life.
布里克死前您留意到有什么变化吗
Did you notice any changes in Brick before he died --
他生活中出现了什么新的人或事物吗
You know, anyone, anything new in his life?
我想没有
No, no. I don't think so.
也没有新的喜好
So, no new interests?
飞蝇钓鱼  集邮  超自然什么的
Fly fishing, stamp collecting, the occult?
超自然
The occult?
举个例子而已
As a "For instance."
没有
No.
全是老样子
Everything was just as it had been.
不好意思  我恐怕得告辞了
I'm sorry, but I'm afraid my time is up.
大学要以布里克的名字命名一幢新体育馆
The university is naming a new athletic building after Brick.
我不能迟到
I can't be late.
当然了  最后一个问题
Of course. Just one more question.
问题总是问不完的  对吗
There is always one more question in life, isn't there?
依我的经验是如此
That's what I find.
她不愿多说  对吗
Oh, she didn't want to say much, did she?
-见鬼  -怎么了
- Son of a bitch. - What?
来了  又出事了
There it is. It happened.
别告诉我博尔德又有人被掏心了
Come on, don't tell me someone had their heart ripped out here in Boulder.
行  那我就不说了
All right, then I won't tell you.
你在这儿干什么  兰达
What are you doing here, Randa?
你知道我喜欢待在家附近
You know I like to stay close to the mother ship.
我看见门前有辆车  就从后门进来了
I saw a car out front, so I came in the back.
是警察
Cops?
或许世人仍然沉迷于布里克的死吧
I suppose Brick's death continues to fascinate.
丑话说在前头
So we're clear...
你说话还很谨慎吗
You're still being very careful about what you say?
我老了  兰达  但不傻
I'm old, Randa, not an idiot.
我只想保护布里克
I'm just trying to protect Brick.
我也是
And so am I.
布里克的心脏在这里跳动着
Brick's heart beats inside here now.
布里克给了我新生命  我能感觉到他
Brick gave me new life. I can feel him.
所以我才搬来博尔德
It's why I moved to Boulder...
靠近这里
to be near here.
我会像布里克一样照顾你
And I'll watch out for you like Brick did.
我不需要你的关心
I don't need your concern.
我们唇齿相依  而布里克需要我们
We need each other, and Brick needs us.
你保住我们的小秘密
You keep our little secret safe,
我们三个人就会相安无事
and the three of us will be just fine.
好吧  莫瑞森教授  帮大忙了
All right, Professor Morrison, that does it.
联调局向您致敬
The FBI thanks you.
对  我一定会想办法请您当技术顾问
Yes, I am totally looking into adding you as a technical advisor.
没错  有医保
Yeah, i-it comes with a medical plan.
好的  再见
All right, goodbye.
他打来了
He come through?
是的
Yeah, he did.
是这么回事  疯子亚瑟・斯温森
All right, so, here's what crazy Arthur Swenson
喋喋不休说的话
was babbling over and over.
首先  的确是消失的语言
Um, first, it is a dead language --
古玛雅语
Ancient Mayan.
那真是消失得无迹可寻
Doesn't get much deader than that.
亚瑟说的是"圣主卡卡奥已降生"
So, what Arthur was saying was "The divine God Cacao is born."
卡卡奥
Cacao?
对  卡卡奥  玛雅的玉米之神
Cacao. Yeah, the Mayan God of maize --
玉米  玉米棒子
Corn, the big crop.
卡卡奥是最强大的神
See, Cacao was the most powerful God
因为玉米对玛雅人来说是最重要的
because maize was the most important thing to the Mayas.
当然除此之外还有迫害与杀戮
Well, that and torturing and killing everyone in sight.
也就是说  我们找的
So, this is what we're looking for,
是个有几千年文明的玉米之神
is a thousand-year-old culture's God of corn?
我想是的
Uh, I guess.
无论如何  我们最好尽快除掉它
Well, whatever it is, we better cap it quick,
不然下一个就轮到凤凰城有人被掏心了
or somebody in Phoenix is next up to get their heart yanked.
凤凰城也有人接受了布里克的捐赠
Someone in Phoenix got a piece of Brick?
对  我查到了名字  刚发邮件给警察
Yeah, I got a name. Just e-mailed the cops.
失踪人口  吉米・唐
他们有答复了
Just heard back from them.
这人已失踪多日
They haven't seen the guy in days.
又收到了一封邮件
Uh, oh, got another e-mail here, too.
这封是给你的
This one is for you.
一所大学发来的
From a university.
答复有关录取的一些问题
Answering questions about admissions.
我只是想了解情况  看看我的选择
Just something I'm looking into. An option.
你真打算退出了
You're seriously talking about hanging it up?
我没说要退出  迪恩
I'm not talking about anything, Dean.
我只是在考虑其他的选择
I'm just looking at options.
我们怎么办  去凤凰城
So, what, should we just go to Phoenix
到处转悠  等这家伙自己露面
and chase our tails until this guy shows his face?
不用  布里克・霍姆斯是事情的关键
No. Uh, Brick Holmes is the way into this.
埃莉诺・霍姆斯是死也不会开口的
Eleanor Holmes was doing her damndest not to tell us a thing.
不过  话题转的很巧妙
Nice job on changing the subject, though.
命名仪式十点结束
All right, naming ceremony's over at 10:00.
我们得速战速决
We got to get in and out.
-去主卧  -好
- Master bedroom. - Yeah.
衣柜
Closets.
布里克的衣柜
Brick's closet.
看来一年没人动过了
Looks like the stuff hasn't been touched in a year.
好家伙  把这些东西拿去易趣网卖多好
Man, what this stuff would go for on e-Bay
萨姆  你要是知道
Hey, Sammy, would it totally crush you
布里克不是天生金发会不会崩溃啊
to know that your boy Brick wasn't a natural blond?
迪恩  有件事很诡异
Dean, this is really weird.
你发现什么了
What do you got?
我不知道  这是埃莉诺的衣柜吗
I don't know. Is this Eleanor's closet?
他母亲的衣柜怎么会在这里  你确定吗
Why would his mother's closet be in here? Are you sure?
你看
Check this out.
我们今天跟她谈话的时候她穿的就是这件
This is what she was wearing today when we talked to her.
说不定是布里克死后她搬进来住了
Maybe she moved into Brick's room after he died.
或者
Or...
谢了  迪恩
Thanks, Dean.
那画面现在永久地刻在我眼睛上了
Now that image is permanently etched into my retinas.
这才对嘛
That's what I'm talking about.
我就知道他家里会有这样的地方
I knew he'd have something like this in his house.
好东西不少啊
This is a lot of hardware.
好吧  有橄榄球奖杯我能理解
Okay, the football trophies I get,
但这些其他的东西呢
but there's a lot of other stuff here --
棒球  拳击  赛车
I mean, baseball, boxing, race-car driving.
他是个粉丝
He was a fan.
他尊敬所有的运动员
Any kind of athlete -- he respected them.
你看他这里所有的旧物
I mean, look at all the old stuff he's got --
板球棒  高尔夫球棒
A cricket mallet, golf clubs,
剑道剑  射箭器材
a Kendo sword, archery equipment.
看这个
Hey, look at this.
都一样
They're all the same.
"亲爱的贝琪"
"Dearest Betsy..." Blah blah blah.
贝琪是谁
Who's Betsy?
我不知道  女朋友
I don't know. Girlfriend?
埃莉诺没有提到贝琪
Eleanor didn't mention a Betsy.
这封看起来很旧
This one looks old.
"亲爱的贝琪  集训第三天
Uh, "Dearest Betsy, third day of training camp.
长跑练习有进步  在练习左刺拳
"Roadwork improving. Working on my left jab.
他们说舒格・雷那孩子会很厉害"
They say this kid Sugar Ray is gonna be tough."
舒格・雷
Sugar Ray?
舒格・雷・罗宾逊: 世界中量级  轻中量级及轻量级拳击冠军
姓罗宾逊的那个
As in Robinson?
他打比赛不是在四十年代吗
Didn't he box in, like, the '40s?
签名都一样吗
Is it signed the same?
是的  "爱你  我"
Yeah. "Love, me."
这封  "亲爱的贝琪  又上路了
Here. "Dearest Betsy, on the road again.
亲爱的  不在你身边的日子真难熬
"So hard to be away from you, honey.
打败红袜队就会回到你身边"
Will give the Red Sox hell and get back to you."
波士顿红袜队: 美国职棒大联盟棒球队
"亲爱的贝琪"
"Dearest Betsy..."
"亲爱的贝琪
"Dearest Betsy,
勒芒今年太不随人愿了  一直在下雨"
Le Mans will be a bitch this year with all the rain..."
法国勒芒: 每年6月举行"勒芒24小时耐力赛"
"费城人队很厉害  但是我们会更厉害"
"...the Phillies are tough, but we're looking to be tougher..."
费城人队: 美国职棒大联盟球队
"让道奇队觉得他们不该离开布鲁克林"
"...them Dodgers will wish they never left Brooklyn..."
道奇队: 美国职棒大联盟球队  成军于纽约布鲁克林
"期待周五在花园最棒的高尔夫之夜"
"...looking for my best gal friday night at the garden..."
旧金山俱乐部
"我们的澳线打得艰难
"...our o-line hung tough.
我在那儿花了一整天"
I had all day back there..."
"阿兰・普罗斯特在直线赛道上就是个怪物"
"...Alain Prost is a monster in the straightaway..."
阿兰・普罗斯特: 法国著名的一级方程式赛车手
-"亲爱的贝琪"  -"亲爱的贝琪"
- "Dearest Betsy..." - "Dearest Betsy..."
"爱你  我"
"Love, me."
等下  这封看起来是近期的
Wait, this one looks recent.
"亲爱的贝琪
"Dearest Betsy...
我真厌倦了这一切"
So tired of it all."
听着
Hey.
我查了那些奖杯上的名字  过来看看
I pulled up the names on those trophies. Check it out.
听着
Hey.
我查了那些奖杯上的名字  过来看看
I pulled up the names on those trophies. Check it out.
好了  布里克・霍姆斯  橄榄球运动员
All right, Brick Holmes -- football player.
查理・卡内斯  赛车手
Charlie Karnes -- race-car driver.
戴维・萨缪尔森  棒球运动员
Davey Samuelson -- baseball player.
凯利・杜兰  拳击手
Kelly Duran -- boxer.
-四个不同的人  对吧  -对
- Four different guys, right? - Okay.
看这个
Check this out.
同样的黑眼睛  同样的颧骨  鼻子和嘴
Same dark eyes, same cheekbones, nose, mouth.
等下  你是说这四个
Wait, are you saying that these four guys
看起来都是二十多岁的人
who all look to be in their mid-20s
且有七十年的跨度  可能是同一个人
and go back 70 years could be the same guy?
95岁高龄的布里克・霍姆斯够厉害啊
For a 95-year-old, Brick Holmes could take a hit.
那么  如果这些运动员都是同一个人
So, if all those athletes were the same guy,
他是怎么做到的呢
how'd he pull it off?
出现  然后离开  然后换个新样子再回来
Appear, then go away and come back with a new look?
卡卡奥  玉米神
Cacao, the, uh, the -- the maize God --
-是玛雅人  对吗  -对
- was Mayan, right? - Yeah.
玛雅人善于战争  酷刑和征服
The Maya were all about war and torture and conquest...
还有运动
and sports.
这上面说  "他们对运动员有如国王
It says, "Their athletes were treated like kings.
玛雅运动员献祭卡卡奥的方式是
"The Mayan jocks made sacrifices to Cacao by --"
做好准备了吗
Ready for this?
杀死祭品  掏出他的心脏  吃掉它
"Killing a victim, pulling out his heart, and eating it."
做好准备了吗
Ready for this?
杀死祭品  掏出他的心脏  吃掉它
"Killing a victim, pulling out his heart, and eating it."
他们深信这样的仪式会给他们
They believed the rituals gave them
战胜对手的强大力量
super-charged power over their opponents.
是啊  但那也不能永葆青春啊
Yeah, but they didn't stay young forever.
所以呢
So, what?
也许布里克也许和这个卡卡奥做了什么交易
Maybe Brick just made some kind of deal with this Cacao?
我们以前也见过
Well, we've seen it before --
人们和魔鬼或神o做交易
People making deals with demons, gods.
也许只要他持续献祭
I mean, maybe he stayed young and strong
他就能保持年轻和强壮
so long as his sacrifices kept coming.
记得他那些古董运动器材吗
Remember all that antique sports equipment he had?
这家伙也许可以追溯到玛雅时期
This guy could go back to the Mayan days.
史上最棒的四分卫之一
So, one of the greatest QBs to ever play the game
有九百多岁了
was over 900 years old.
布里克的事说得通了
Well, that explains Brick,
但是那些移植了他器官的人呢
but what about the mooks carrying his spare parts?
也许咒语对全身都起了作用
Maybe the spell went along for the ride
影响了那些得到他器官的人
and infected the people who got his organs.
记得保罗・海耶斯说过
Remember how Paul Hayes said
他因为健康问题而改变了他的生活
he had a health scare that changed his life?
也许咒语可以迫使他继续进行那个仪式
I mean, maybe the spell could compel him to keep carrying out the ritual.
有点像被狼人咬了一下
Sort of like getting bit by a werewolf.
一旦感染  你就得去做必须做的事情
I mean, once you're infected, you do what you got to do,
特别是如果结果对你有利
especially if you like the results.
没错  除了老亚瑟  那个敬业的警察
Right, except old Arthur, the dedicated cop,
他不能接受  所以疯了
couldn't handle it and went nuts.
布里克・霍姆斯  吃心人  谁能想到
Brick Holmes, a heart eater. Who knew?
抱歉  伙计
Hey, sorry, buddy.
站得越高  摔得越狠
The mighty -- they fall hard, huh?
至少他没和他妈上床
Well, at least he wasn't sleeping with his mother.
是的  真棒  萨姆  找到了一线希望
Yeah, good, Sam. Find the silver lining.
不  说真的  看
No, seriously. Look.
"拳击手凯利・杜兰
"Fighter Kelly Duran
第二轮淘汰赛时  妻子贝琪上前祝贺"
is congratulated on a second-round knockout by wife Betsy."
"亲爱的贝琪"
"Dearest Betsy."
你好  埃莉诺
Hello, Eleanor.
或许你更希望我们喊你贝琪
Or would you rather us call you Betsy?
埃莉诺  无辜的人在死去
Look, Eleanor, innocent people are dying.
而且这不会停止  除非我们阻止
And they're gonna continue to die until we stop it.
你知道这一年发生的凶案吗
Did you know about the murders over the past year?
不  不知道  我发誓
No. I didn't. I swear.
我以为  布里克死了  就会停止
I thought when -- when Brick died, it would be over.
帮帮我们
Help us.
贝琪  你也不想布里克留下这样的遗产
Betsy, this is not what you want Brick's legacy to be.
他的玛雅名字是因尤
His Mayan name was Inyo.
大约一千年前  他是个骄傲的年轻运动员
He was a proud young athlete nearly 1,000 years ago.
他为运动而生
He lived for sport
不想结束这种风光的生活
and never wanted his days in the sun to end.
于是他找了个大祭司和玉米之神做了笔交易
So he arranged a bargain with the God Cacao through a high priest.
永驻青春
Stay young forever.
只要祭祀不停止
As long as the sacrifices continued,
一年两次
twice a year --
一次祭奠种植  一次祭奠收获
Once for the planting, once for harvest.
你什么时候发现的
When did you find out about this?
直到我开始年老色衰  布里克他
Not until I began to age and -- and Brick --
就是凯利  那是我们相遇时他的名字
Kelly, as he was when I met him --
却毫无变化
did not.
只是到了那时
But by that time,
布里克的内心已经变了
Brick himself had changed...inside.
他已经不再是
He wasn't just the warrior
只为战斗而生的战士了
whose only reason for living was combat.
他
He --
我们曾经深爱着对方
We were deeply, deeply in love.
爱得如此深切  以至于
So in love, I'm ashamed to say,
当我发现
that when I found out that --
我的丈夫是如何永葆青春的
how my husband stayed young and strong,
我选择了漠然视之
I chose to ignore it.
你和布里克必须时不时隐姓埋名
You and Brick had to go underground
好掩饰你们的秘密  对吗
from time to time to hide your secret, right?
大概每十年吧
Every 10 years or so,
他会以新面孔  新名字再度露面
he would re-emerge with a new look, a new name.
而我  做过他妻子
And me, I was the wife,
做过隐姓埋名的女人
and I was the woman in hiding,
到了四十岁的时候
and then, when I got into my 40s,
成了布里克的母亲
I became Brick's mother.
也就是埃莉诺
Eleanor.
我太累了
I am so tired.
你们想象不到这担子有多重
You can't imagine the burden of it all.
我想布里克也受够了
I think even Brick was through,
他知道我活不了多久了
he could see the end of my days were at hand,
虽然他之前也曾独自生活过很久
and...he had lived centuries all alone,
但我觉得他已无法承受没有我的日子
but I don't think he could bear the thought of life without me.
所以他才会冲下了那座桥
That's why he drove off that bridge.
你们一定认为我是个怪物
You must think I'm a monster.
不会
No.
不会  你嫁的那个才是
No, just that you married one.
现在的问题是
Well, see, here's the deal.
我们要对付八个杀手  而不是一个
Now there are eight killers out there that we have to deal with, not just one.
我看未必
I don't think so.
什么  怎么说
What? Why not?
布里克常说心是关键
Brick used to say the heart was key.
那才是祭祀的重点
That was the focus of the sacrifice.
你是说  如果我们能让布里克的心停止跳动
Are you saying that if we stop Brick's beating heart,
那就能了结整件事
then we could stop the whole thing?
你知道那个接受了他心脏的人在哪吗
Do you know where the person is who has the heart?
你知道吗
Do you know?
不是吧
Really?
我们的头号恶魔是个脱衣舞娘
Our king daddy monster is a stripper?
这么做应该很有把握吧
We're pretty sure this is gonna work, right?
只要埃莉诺没说错
Well, as long as Eleanor knows what she's talking about.
你觉得布里克撞车的时候
You think Brick thought maybe he'd burn to nothing
是不是想烧成灰
when he crashed that car?
是的  可他没有  于是我们得代劳
Yeah, but he didn't, which brings us here.
闻到没有
Smell that?
你真恶心
You're gross.
埃莉诺让你们来的  对吗
Eleanor sent you, right?
我猜到她可能会扛不住把我说出来
I figured she'd probably break and give me up.
当然了  她会为此付出代价
This won't end well for her, of course.
你们也不会有好果子吃
Not that it's gonna end well for you.
你觉得我们会让你得手吗
Oh, now, you don't think we're gonna let you do that, do you?
"我们"
"We"?
我就是你们要找的凤凰城的那个人
I'm the guy from Phoenix you were looking for.
你们几个还挺能打的
Oh, you guys are stronger than you look.
移植手术附加礼物  还有  我常健身
Comes with the package. Plus, I work out a lot.
你们肯定想不到我原来什么样
You can't imagine who I was before.
佐治亚州的一个羞嗒嗒  怯生生的
This shy, awkward little thing from Georgia
患有心脏病的女孩
with a heart condition.
之后我做了移植手术
Then I had the surgery.
我变成了战士公主西娜
I became freaking Xena: Warrior Princess.
古希腊女英雄
我上学时都不敢解剖青蛙
I couldn't dissect a frog in high school.
但向卡卡奥献祭
But sacrificing to Cacao?
比上床更美妙
Better than sex.
所以  假如我动作够缓  慢慢享受
So, if I go real slow and take my time and enjoy this,
我能让你在死前看见自己跳动的心脏
I can actually show you your own beating heart before you die.
我们该走了
Well, we better get going,
只想告诉你事情已经彻底解决了
we just wanted you to know that it really is over now.
无论如何  总得解决
Well, it had to be, one way or the other.
我还以为你们也许失败了
I half thought you might fail
兰达会来找我索命
and Randa would come after me.
不管是哪样  我总算能得到安宁
Either way, I'd finally be at peace.
你多保重  埃莉诺
You take care of yourself, Eleanor.
做回老本行
Wow. Back in business.
大获全胜
Got the win.
承认吧  感觉不错对吗
Admit it -- feels good, huh?
我一直在想兰达说过
You know, I was thinking about what Randa said about, uh,
感觉像个战士的那番话
you know, what it feels like to be a warrior.
我能理解  兄弟  真的
I get it, man, I do.
我知道  我知道你理解
I know. I know you do.
可我不
I don't.
现在不理解了  也许从来就没理解过
Not anymore. Hell, maybe I never did.
萨姆  你就非得破坏气氛吗
Come on, Sam, don't ruin my buzz, would you?
迪恩  等这事一结束
Dean, listen, when this is over --
等凯文和石碑的事一结束
When we close up shop on Kevin and the tablet --
我就不干了  我说真的
I'm done. I mean that.
不行  你不能不干
No, you don't.
迪恩  我不当猎人的那一年
Dean, the year that I took off,
我拥有了我从没有过的东西
I had something I've never had.
正常人的生活
A normal life.
我有机会尝到了那种滋味
I mean, I got to see what that felt like.
那是我想要的
I want that.
我也曾经得到过
I had that.
我想那只是你现在的感受
I think that's just how you feel right now.
艾米利亚  艾米利亚  别开玩笑了
Amelia! Amelia, this isn't funny.
艾米利亚
Amelia!
小乱
Riot?
Riot!
生日快乐
Happy birthday!
这是什么
What is this?
你没见过生日蛋糕啊
You've never seen a birthday cake before?
坐啊
Sit.
吃吧
Eat.